GABRIEL ZURITA RUBY DEVELOPER

> CONTACT

gabezurita@gmail.com

www.gabo.online

**** 315-395-3987

f gzurita 💆 gabezurita

in gabezurita 🖸 gabezurita

> SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript

DATABASES

PostgreSQL

SQLite

MySQL

JQL

TESTING

RSpec

Jasmine

Capybara

METHODOLOGIES

Test Driven Development

Agile Development

Object-Oriented Design

Git Workflow

FRAMEWORKS

Rails

Sinatra

Bootstrap

AngularJS

FRONT-END

HTML

CSS

jQuery

AJAX

MEDIA

Photography

Adobe Suite

CRM

Salesforce

DATA ANALYSIS

Regression Analysis ArcGIS

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

Native fluency in Spanish and English

> SUMMARY

Hello! I'm Gabriel, a Ruby developer with microfinance and nonprofit experience, living in Washington, DC. I'm currently working at Optoro as a Platform Stability Analyst, playing my part to build more sustainable solutions for reverse logistics.

> PROJECTS

OPTORO JIRA AUTOMATION AND REPORTING

Optoro Jira Automation and Reporting is a Ruby gem that is used by Optoro's tech teams to add time tracking functionality to Jira Cloud and automate various functions of Optoro's Platform Stability team. The gem uses the Jira API and various other gems to update Jira issue custom fields with Service Level Agreement and time tracking data. This automation is used to send notifications to product managers, developers, issue watchers, and support personnel to help keep issues on track and to meet contractual SLAs. The data this gem produces is used to create Jira views for tech teams, to analyze tech team performance, and to create reports through scripts that inform stability and scaling decisions.

GLOBAL HOST

A mobile app that lets users connect with local guides in foreign cities who share common interests and create an itinerary for a day's visit so as to experience that city like a local. Global Host was an eight-day, fourperson final project for Dev Bootcamp. It was built on Rails, utilized the Google Maps JavaScript API, relied on Materialize CSS for visual elements, and was consistently tested using Codeship continuous integration. Visit the live app at global-host.herokuapp.com and view the project code on github

> EXPERIENCE

Platform Stability Analyst · OPTORO

Nov 2016 to Current · Washington, D.C.

Optoro's Platform Stability team is responsible for ensuring that our systems are available around the clock. As a technical analyst on the team, I:

- Develop and maintain a Ruby gem that sends Service Level Management notifications to product
 managers, engineers, issue watchers, and support personnel. The data produced by this gem are used to
 populate Jira SLA views, to analyze tech team performance, and to automatically generate reports—
 features that save Optoro \$3,000 in Jira user costs each month.
- · Collaborate directly with engineers to deliver enterprise-grade stability in all of Optoro's products
- Develop and monitor dashboards, automated alerts, and other tools to effectively monitor and report on system uptime, server capacity utilization, system scaling, SLA metrics, and other vital business and technical metrics
- Inform stability and scaling decisions by analyzing system reliability and sprint capacity metrics in monthly reports for CTO, engineering leads, and product managers

Web Developer in Training · DEV BOOTCAMP

Feb 2016 to Jul 2016 · Chicago

In Dev Bootcamp, I spent 6 intense, immersive months studying back-end and front-end languages and frameworks. We applied agile and test-driven development practices as we pair programmed projects together throughout the course using JavaScript (raw, jQuery, AJAX), Ruby, Rails, Git, HTML, and CSS. I also strengthened team skills like communication, empathy, and effective feedback in order foster optimal teamwork environments both in and beyond the program.

Operations Agent · YMCA OF METROPOLITAN CHICAGO

Mar 2014 to Nov 2015 · Chicago

At the YMCA, I collaborated effectively with various YMCA teams and locations to increase the quality of services and standardize processes and policies, managing customer relations across 23 membership centers. In addition, I performed research and compiled performance metrics for the Director of Operations, and continuously revised engagement scripts to improve member experience, retention, and satisfaction.

> VOLUNTEERING

Associate Board Member · THE ARTS OF LIFE

Jul 2015 to Feb 2016

The Associate Board is made up of a network of young Chicago area professionals who lead fundraising events and actively volunteer for The Arts of Life, a nonprofit that helps disabled adults create and promote their artwork.

Finance Lead · LAKES OF FIRE CAMP NATURAL WONDER

Mar 2014 to Jul 2016

Headed team and raised \$15,000 for event expenses and infrastructure on yearly a basis, coordinating 120 volunteers in funds disbursement and responsibilities. Collaborated on project proposals for art grants, one which won \$1350.

> EDUCATION

Middle Tennessee State University

Bachelor of Science Economics | Global Studies 2009

 $3.784\ \mbox{Cumulative GPA}$ | Graduated magna cum laude, top 5% of class.